Water Demon.
Démon d'eau.
Ice Dragon.
Dragon de glace.
Lesser Warlord of Ka'a.
Petit Guerrier de Ka'a.
Not so fast.
Pas si Vite.
Infinite Sheldon.
Sheldon de l'Infini.
Infinite Sheldon?
Sheldon de l'Infini ?
Yes. Infinite Sheldon defeats all other cards...
Le Sheldon de l'Infini bat les autres cartes
...and does not violate the rule against homemade cards. I made it at work.
et ne va pas à l'encontre des règles que j'ai inventées.
You understand why people don't wanna play with you?
Tu sais pourquoi personne ne joue avec toi ?
Although it's a question I've been pondering since preschool.
Je me le demande depuis la crèche.
-Hey.
- Salut.
Hey.
Salut.
Hey, your copy of Science magazine was in my mailbox.
Ton exemplaire de Science était chez moi.
-Oh, thanks. -Check it out.
- Merci. - Regarde.
All about planets this month.
Il parle des planètes.
That's an atom.
C‘est un atome.
Agree to disagree.
Je suis en désaccord.
That's what I love about science: There's no one right answer.
C‘est pour ça que j'aime la science. Il y a plus d‘une réponse.
-So you and Zack again, huh? -Yeah, yeah, me and Zack again.
- Donc, toi et Zack encore ? - Oui, moi et Zack encore.
Were we here earlier?
On est déjà venus ?
-Okay, we should go. -Not yet.
- On y va. - Non.
I wanna talk science with the science dudes.
Je veux parler de science avec eux.
Oh, and the science dudes wanna talk science with you.
Et on veut parler de science avec toi.
What do you wanna talk about? Rocks? Dinosaurs?
Quel sujet ? Les roches ? Les dinosaures ?
Our friend the beaver?
Notre ami le castor ?
I saw this great thing on the Discovery Channel.
J'ai regardé Discovery Channel.
Turns out that if you kill a starfish, it'll just come back to life.
Si on tue une étoile de mer, elle revient à la vie.
Was the starfish wearing boxer shorts?
Elle portait un caleçon ?
Because you might've been watching Nickelodeon.
Tu regardais peut-étre Nickelodeon.
No, I'm almost sure that it was the Discovery Channel.
Non, je suis presque sûr que c'était Discovery Channel.
It was a great show. They also said dolphins might be smarter than people.
Les dauphins seraient plus intelligents que les hommes.
They might be smarter than some people.
Que certains hommes.
Well, maybe we can do an experiment to find out.
On pourrait faire une expérience.
That's easy enough.
C‘est assez simple.
We'd need a large tank of water, a hoop to jump through...
Il faut un bac d'eau, un cerceau pour sauter
...and a bucket of whatever bite-size treats you find tasty.
et un seau rempli de friandises que tu aimes bien.
I don't get it.
Je n'ai pas compris.
Adolphin might.
Un dauphin, si.
Oh, I see. You guys are inferring that I'm stupid.
Je vois. Vous dites que je suis bête.
That's not correct. We were implying it.
lncorrect. C'était implicite.
You then inferred it.
C‘est toi qui l'as dit.
ZACK: Let's go.
On s'en va.
For a group of guys who claim they spent most of their lives...
Pour des garçons qui ont passé leur vie
...being bullied, you can be real jerks. Shame on all of you.
à être maltraités, vous êtes des abrutis. Honte à vous.
What the hell did I do?
Qu‘est—ce que j'ai fait ?
You laughed.
Tu as rigolé.
You think Penny's right? Were we bullying Zack?
Penny a raison ? On l‘a maltraité ?
No. I know bullying.
Non. Je sais ce que c'est.
He left here unswirlied, and his ass crack was underpants-free.
Il est ressorti d‘ici en bon état et avec son slip.
And nobody drew a penis on his forehead.
Sans dessin de pénis sur le front.
That happened to you?
Ça t‘est arrivé ?
First day of Cricket Camp.
Premier jour de colonie.
They drew it so the testicles were my eyes.
Les testicules me tombaient dans les yeux.
I don't know, we might owe the guy an apology.
On lui doit des excuses.
So go apologize.
Va t'excuser.
-Why me? -You started it. We just piled on.
- Pourquoi moi ? - Tu as commencé. On a surenchéri.
-What would I even say? -"Zack, I'm sorry you're stupid.
- Je lui dis quoi ? - "Zack, désolé que tu sois bête.
Have a Milk Dud."
Prends un Milk Dud."
-A Milk Dud? -Yeah.
- Un Milk Dud ? -Oui.
Milk Duds, with their self-deprecating name...
Avec leur nom auto-dévalorisant
...and remarkably mild flavor...
et leur goût exquis,
...are the most apologetic of the boxed candies.
ce sont les meilleures friandises pour s'excuser.
Well, I got a better idea. We're all responsible. I say we all go.
Nous sommes tous responsables. Allons—y ensemble.
Come on, who's with me?
Venez. Qui me suit ?
Free comic books to anyone who comes with me.
Bandes dessinées gratuites pour ceux qui Viennent.
I might get punched. You really wanna miss that?
Il va me frapper. Qui veut rater ça ?
-Junior Mints are pretty apologetic. -You're embarrassing yourself.
- Les Junior Mints sont mieux. - Tu te ridiculises.
Penny.
Penny.
-What? -We came to talk to Zack. Hey, Zack.
- Quoi ? - On est venus parler à Zack.
What do you want?
Que voulez-vous ?
The stuff we were saying before, we were just kidding around.
Tout ce qu'on a dit, c‘était une plaisanterie.
No, you weren't. You were making fun of me.
Non. Vous vous moquiez de moi.
Come on. That's what we do. We give each other a hard time.
Allez. C‘est ce qu'on fait entre nous. On y passe tous.
Hey, Sheldon, you look like a praying mantis.
Sheldon, tu ressembles à une mante religieuse.
-That's very hurtful. -See?
- C‘est très blessant. - Tu vois ?
I don't know. Still wasn't very nice.
Ce n‘était pas sympa.
Milk Dud?
Milk Dud ?
Oh, I love Milk Duds.
J‘adore les Milk Dud.
Okay, we're cool.
C‘est bon, c‘est oublié.
Junior Mints.
Junior Mints.
-You wanna have a beer? -We're on our way...
- Une bière ? - Nous allions
-...to the comic-book store, so.... -Leonard's buying.
- à la librairie... - Leonard paie.
Really? I haven't been to a comic-book store in literally a million years.
Je n‘y suis pas allé depuis littéralement un million d‘années.
Literally? Literally a million years?
Littéralement ? Littéralement un million d'années ?
-You wanna go with them? -No.
- Tu y vas ? - Non.
-Okay, see you later. -What--? Wait, wait, wait.
- A plus tard alors. - Quoi ? Attends.
You're ditching me to go look at comic books?
Tu me laisses tomber pour y aller ?
-Are you mad at me? -l'm not happy.
- Tu es furieuse ? - Je ne suis pas ravie.
Milk Dud?
Milk Dud ?
Wow, this place is awesome.
Cet endroit est génial.
Where do they keep the Archies?
Où sont les Archie ?
In the bedrooms of 10-year-old girls, where they belong.
A leur place. Dans le lit des fillettes de dix ans.
You're thinking old-school Archie. It's much more sophisticated now.
Tu penses àla Vieille édition. C‘est mieux maintenant.
Like, there's two universes.
Il y a deux univers.
Archie's married to Betty in one and Veronica in the other.
Archie a deux femmes: Betty et Veronica.
-Midge is even breaking up with Moose. -No.
- Midge rompt même avec Moose. - Non.
About time, right?
Il était temps, non ?
STUART: Hey. LEONARD: Hey.
- Salut.
You guys finally chip in for a bodyguard?
Vous avez engagé un garde du corps ?
No. This is Zack. He's a friend of ours.
Non. C‘est Zack. Un de nos amis.
Zack, this is Stuart. He owns the store.
Voici Stuart, le propriétaire.
Wow, lucky you.
Vous avez dela chance.
Yeah. I work 70 hours a week and average $1.65 an hour.
Je travaille 70 heures par semaine pour 1,65 $ de l'heure.
Sweet.
C‘est génial.
Is that sarcasm?
C‘est sarcastique ?
No, it's an indictment of the American education system.
Non. C‘est une inculpation du système éducatif.
-The Archies are over here. -Yippee.
Les Archie sont là-bas.
So are you guys coming to my New Year's Eve costume party?
Vous venez toujours à mon réveillon costumé ?
Of course. We're coming as the Justice League of America.
Bien sûr. On sera la Ligue de justice d‘Amérique.
Switching it up from last year when we came as the Justice League of America.
Ça change de l'an dernier où on était
To that point, it occurs to me that we might have an opportunity...
A ce sujet, je pense que nous avons une chance
...to finally snare Best Group Costume...
de gagner le prix de meilleur costume
...if we shore up our weak link, which is clearly Leonard as Superman.
si nous consolidons notre maillon faible : Leonard en Superman.
Hey, I got new boots this year. Guaranteed to add 3 inches.
J'ai des nouvelles chaussures. Ça me donne 8 cm de plus.
That's sad.
C‘est triste.
Let's ask ourselves, is there anyone we know...
Demandons-nous s'il n‘y a pas quelqu'un
...who would make a more manly and convincing son of Krypton?
qui ferait un fils de Krypton plus masculin et plus convaincant ?
Than Leonard in high-heeled boots?
Que Leonard sur des talons ?
Howard's mother in high-heeled boots?
La mère d'Howard sur des talons ?
l was thinking specifically of the gentleman over there...
Je pensais plutôt à l‘homme là-bas
...moving his lips as he enjoys the latest exploits of Betty and Veronica.
qui bouge les lèvres en se délectant des derniers exploits de Betty.
Zack?
Zack ?
He's the only person we know with actual muscles.
C‘est la seule personne qui ait de vrais muscles.
You can't replace me with Zack.
Vous ne pouvez pas me remplacer par Zack.
Why not? Penny did it.
Pourquoi pas ? Penny l‘a bien fait.
Yeah. She seems happier. Why wouldn't we be?
Elle est plus heureuse. Pourquoi pas nous ?
Score. I got an Archie, Betty and Veronica, and a Jughead.
Gagné ! J'ai un Archie, Betty et Veronica et un Jughead.
All set for my weekend number twos.
Tout est prêt pour mon week-end.
Congratulations.
Félicitations.
Zack, how would you like to be Superman?
Zack, aimerais-tu être Superman ?
I don't know. Sounds like a lot of responsibility.
Je ne sais pas. C‘est beaucoup de responsabilités.
Fine, if Zack's gonna be Superman, I wanna be Green Lantern.
S'il est Superman, je veux être Green Lantern.
-But I'm Green Lantern. -You can be Aquaman.
- Je suis Green Lantern. - Aquaman.
RAJESH: I don't wanna be Aquaman. He sucks.
Je ne veux pas être Aquaman. Il pue.
He sucks underwater.
Il pue l'océan.
He sucks fish pee.
Il pue la pisse de poisson.
Excuse me. I believe Aquaman uses his telepathic powers...
Je croyais qu‘Aquaman utilisait ses pouvoirs télépathiques
...to request the fish do their business elsewhere.
pour obliger les poissons à être propres.
-Hey, babe. -l'm still mad at you.
- Bébé. - Je suis furieuse.
You won't be when you hear the great news.
Ça va changer. Ecoute—ga.
-What great news? -We're going to a costume party...
- Quoi ? - Nous allons à un bal costumé
...at the comic-book store on New Year's Eve...
à la librairie pour le réveillon
...and you get to be Wonder Woman.
et tu seras Wonder Woman.
Complete with bulletproof bracelets and Lasso of Truth.
Avec des bracelets pare-halles et un lasso.
Invisible Plane sold separately.
Mais sans avion invisible.
Okay, why me? Why can't your girlfriend be Wonder Woman?
Pourquoi moi ? Ta petite amie ne peut pas le faire ?
Yeah, well, she and her lab team are under quarantine.
Elle et son équipe sont en quarantaine.
At the Christmas party, they were doing Jell-O shots out of Petri dishes...
A Noël, ils ont mangé dela gelée dans des coupelles
...that used to contain yellow fever.
qui contenaient la fièvre jaune.
Okay. Well, what about your friend Amy?
Et ton amie Amy ?
Amy Farrah Fowler doesn't believe in wearing costumes.
Elle n‘est pas sensible aux déguisements.
She isn't the free spirit I am.
aussi libre d'esprit que moi.
Forget it. I'm not spending my New Year's Eve at a comic-book store...
Oubliez—ça. Je ne passerai pas le réveillon
...wearing a Wonder Woman costume.
déguisée en Wonder Woman.
He says he'll wear it if you'll be Aquaman.
Il le porte si tu fais Aquaman.
What are you doing?
Que fais-tu ?
We're going to be late. I'm pacing nervously.
Nous allons être en retard. Je marche nerveusement.
-You're jogging. -This is how the Flash paces.
- Tu cours. - Flash se déplace ainsi.
-Just chill out, Sheldon. -l'm not Sheldon, I'm the Flash.
- Détends-toi, Sheldon. - Pas Sheldon. Flash.
And now I'm going to the Grand Canyon to scream in frustration.
Je vais au Grand Canyon pour crier ma frustration.
I'm back.
Je suis revenu.
[IN LOW VOICE] I'm Batman.
Je suis Batman.
I hardly think so. The real Caped Crusader...
Je ne crois pas. Le vrai Batman
...calls his crime-fighting cohorts when he's running late.
appelle quand il est en retard.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] I had to walk.
J'ai dû marcher. Raj ne tient pas sur mon scooter.
I've said this before and I'll say it again: Aquaman sucks.
Je l'ai déjà dit etje le répète: Aquaman pue.
ZACK: Look up in the sky.
Regardez dans le ciel. C‘est un oiseau. C‘est un avion.
I forget the rest.
J'ai oublié la suite.
All right, let's get this thing over with.
C‘est bon. Finissons-en avec ça.
I'm sorry, but in what universe is Wonder Woman blond?
Désolé mais dans quel univers Wonder Woman est blonde ?
Relax. No one's gonna be looking at her hair.
Détends-toi. Personne ne regardera ses cheveux.
Costume came with a black wig. Where is it?
Où est la perruque noire ?
-l'm not wearing it. It looks stupid. -We're trying to win a contest.
- Je ne la porterai pas. - On essaie de gagner.
-Forget it. I'm not wearing the wig. -Penny, there's no I in "Justice League."
- Non. Je ne la porterai pas. - Il n‘y a pas de "je" dans la Ligue.
-Well, actually-- -Don't. He's making our case.
- En fait... - Non. Il fait notre affaire.
Okay, babe, you're kind of embarrassing me in front of my friends.
Tu m‘embarrasses devant mes amis.
Okay, you know what? I changed my mind. I'm not going.
J'ai changé d‘avis. Je ne Viens pas.
Looks like someone else is gonna have to be Wonder Woman.
Quelqu‘un d‘autre va devoir faire Wonder Woman.
-Babe, open up. PENNY: I'm not talking to you.
- Bébé, ouvre. - Je ne te parle pas.
Then who are you talking to?
A qui parles-tu alors ?
Babe?
Bébé ?
Penny. Penny. Penny.
Penny. Penny. Penny.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Qu‘est—ce qui ne tourne pas rond chez toi ?
I'm the Flash. I just knocked 30,000 times.
Je suis Flash. J'ai frappé 30 000 fois.
-Okay, what do you want, Sheldon? -I understand why you're upset.
- Que veux-tu ? - Je comprends ta colére.
-Really? -Yes.
- Vraiment ? - Oui.
You're afraid that costume makes you look fat.
Tu as peur de faire grosse dans ce costume.
No. Wha--? Does it?
Non. Quoi ? C‘est le cas ?
Don't worry. Wonder Woman was an Amazon.
Ne t'inquiète pas. Wonder Woman était une Amazone.
And Amazons tend to be very beefy gals.
Et les Amazones étaient des filles bien en chair.
Goodbye, Sheldon.
Au revoir, Sheldon.
But they're not blond, so put on your wig.
Elles n‘étaient pas blondes. Mets ta perruque.
Hello?
Allô ?
Stupid Aquaman.
Stupide Aquaman.
If it makes you feel better, when l was dating Penny...
Si ça peut te consoler, quand je sortais avec elle,
...she used to flip out on me all the time.
elle s'énervait tout le temps.
Whoa, you dated Penny?
Tu es sorti avec elle ?
She didn't tell you?
Elle ne t‘a rien dit ?
She told me she dated a guy named Leonard.
Elle m‘a parlé d'un Leonard.
Who would've thought it was you?
Qui aurait cru que c‘était toi ?
Who else would it be?
Qui d‘autre alors ?
I don't know, somebody bigger and....
Je ne sais pas. Quelqu'un de plus fort et...
Yeah, sure. Why not you?
Oui. Pourquoi pas toi ?
I may have failed.
J'ai dû échouer.
Okay. I guess we just go without a Wonder Woman.
On y va sans Wonder Woman.
-I don't wanna go without Penny. -Oh, great.
- Je n'irai pas sans Penny. - Super.
No Superman, no Wonder Woman.
Pas de Superman non plus.
All we've got is a skinny Flash, an Indian Aquaman...
On a un Flash osseux, un Aquaman indien,
...a nearsighted Green Lantern, and a teeny-tiny Dark Knight.
un Green Lantern myope et un minuscule Chevalier Noir.
Well, obviously, we're no longer a Justice League.
Nous ne sommes plus une Ligue de justice.
We have no choice but to switch to our Muppet Baby costumes.
Nous devons remettre nos costumes de Muppet Baby.
-I call Kermit. -l'm Kermit. You're Scooter.
- Je suis Kermit. - Je suis Kermit. Tu es Scooter.
Oh, man, Scooter sucks.
Scooter pue.
He's the Aquaman of the Muppet Babies.
C‘est l‘Aquaman des Muppet Baby.
No, we can still make this work. Leonard, you talk to Penny.
On peut encore rattraper le coup. Leonard, va lui parler.
What makes you think I can convince her?
Tu crois que j‘y arriverai ?
You got her to have sex with you.
Tu as couché avec elle.
Obviously your superpower is brainwashing.
Ton super—pouvoir fait un lavage de cerveau.
Okay, let me see if I understand this.
Voyons si j'ai bien compris.
You want me to convince my ex-girlfriend to go to a costume party...
Tu veux que je persuade mon ex d‘aller à une soirée déguisée
...with her new boyfriend just so we can win a stupid prize?
avec son nouveau copain pour gagner un prix ?
Yes. And make her wear the black wig. Good luck.
Oui. Et elle doit porter la perruque.
-Go away, Sheldon. LEONARD: It's Leonard.
- Va-t'en, Sheldon. - C‘est Leonard.
Come on, let me just talk to you.
Je veux juste te parler.
It's open.
C‘est ouvert.
-Hey. -l'm not going to that party, Leonard.
- Salut. - Je n'irai pas àla fête.
Okay, listen, you don't have to wear the wig.
Rien ne t'oblige à porter la perruque.
At this party, we're gonna win first prize just by showing up with a girl.
On gagnera rien qu'en étant avec une fille.
It's not the wig.
Ce n‘est pas la perruque.
Did I do something? I mean, I tried to be friends with Zack...
C‘est moi ? J'ai essayé d‘étre ami avec Zack
...like you said, which, believe me, was difficult.
comme tu me l'as demandé et c‘est difficile.
Given how you and me used to be, you know, you and me...
Vu que toi et moi, on était toi et moi
...and now you and him are you and him.
et maintenant toi et lui, vous formez toi et moi.
Okay, look, we're not really "me and him."
On n‘est pas comme ça.
-Then what are you? -I don't know.
- Comment ça ? - Je ne sais pas.
I only started seeing Zack again so I wouldn't be alone on New Year's Eve.
Je revois Zack pour ne pas être seule pour le réveillon.
How pathetic is that?
C‘est pathétique, non ?
Not as pathetic as dressing up like this...
Pas autant qu'être déguisé
...and going to a comic-book store on New Year's Eve.
et passer le réveillon dans une librairie.
You make a cute Green Arrow.
Tu fais un très joli Archer Vert.
Green Lantern.
Green Lantern.
Like there's a difference.
Comme s'il y avait une différence.
There's a big difference.
Une énorme différence.
Arrow.
Arc.
Lantern.
Lanterne.
If Zack and I had just gone to a regular club or a party, it would've been fine.
Si Zack et moi avions passé la soirée ailleurs, ça aurait été.
-But this, with the costumes and you-- -What about me?
- Mais cette soirée et toi... - Moi ?
Nothing. Let's go to the party.
Rien. Allons à cette fête.
How do I look?
Comment je suis ?
I guarantee you'll be the prettiest girl there.
Tu seras la plus belle dela fête.
Okay, the good news is, we have a Wonder Woman.
Bonne nouvelle. Nous avons une Wonder Woman.
RAJESH: Yes. -What's the bad news?
- Oui. - La mauvaise nouvelle ?
Superman probably isn't getting laid tonight.
Superman va se faire larguer ce soir.
And the award for Best Group Costume goes to...
Et le prix du meilleur déguisement de groupe revient à
...Justice League of America...
la Ligue de justice
...number three!
numéro trois!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
Merci ! Merci beaucoup!
Okay, okay. Ten seconds to midnight.
Dix secondes avant minuit.
ALL: Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven. -No, wait, I have a speech.
- Dix, neuf, huit, sept. - Attendez, j'ai un discours.
ALL: Six. Five. Four. -Stop counting.
- Six, cinq, quatre. - Arrêtez.
-This is my moment, dagnabbit. ALL: Three. Two. One.
- C‘est mon moment. - Trois, deux, un, zéro.
I'm not going to say another word until you people settle down!
Je ne dirai plus rien tant que vous ne serez pas calmes.
I'm waiting.
J'attends.
That was a great party.
C‘était une fête géniale.
We should dress like this all the time.
On devrait toujours se déguiser.
Are you high?
Tu as perdu la tête ?
You're being a bully.
Tu deviens méchante.
Whoa, check it out, those guys are breaking into that car.
Regardez. Ces types voient une voiture.
What should we do?
Que devons-nous faire ?
We're the Justice League of America. There's only one thing we can do:
Nous sommes la Ligue de Justice. Il n‘y a qu‘une chose à faire.
Turn around and slowly walk away.
Faire demi-tour et s‘enfuir.
Hold up.
Attendez.
Look, I know our winter thermostat setting is 72 degrees...
Je sais que ton chauffage est réglé à 22°c
...but I'm a little warm, so I'm gonna turn it down.
mais j'ai un peu chaud. Je le baisse.
Good Lord, how you frustrate me, Leonard Hofstadter!
Bon sang, tu m'énerves, Leonard Hofstadter !
Fine.
D‘accord.
[English - us - an]
[French]